Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Annotated Scores, 1828-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Annotated scores 1762-1993, I.; Folder 001-Folder 607
  - Neuwirth, Gösta Von unklaich nach China fur Singstimme und Klaviere, 1973, 4 scores (49 pages each); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and two pianos Second piano part highlighted throughout. One copy is missing the first song. Scores bear different sets of markings. (Box 18, Fold
    Auf leichten fussen -- Mide songs -- Steam lodge song of the sun dance ceremony -- Genügsamkeit -- Sometimes -- Song for the puberty rite of a girl named Cowaka -- Epilog.
  - Nogueira, Ilza Maria Costa Transforms for saxophone quartet and computer generated tape, 1985, 1 score (91 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For saxophone quartet and tape The only markings are on the introductory textual content. Ph. D. dissertation at the University at Buffalo. Includes a two-page summary about the musical work. (Box 18, Folder 0376)
  - Nørgård, Per, 1932- Rapsodi for klaver og orkester: transkription f. 2 Klaverer, 1981, 1 score (28 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For two pianos; originally for piano and orchestra Contains performance markings, including fingerings. Signed by Mikhashoff and dated Aug. 9, 1984, Copenhagen. (Box 18, Folder 0377)
  - Nørgård, Per, 1932- Solo Intimo: sonata, quasi una fantasia per 'cello, op. 8, 1974, 1 score (4 pages); Print (photocopy) Wilhelm Hansen Instrumentation: For solo violoncello Extensively marked with bowings and fingerings. (Box 18, Folder 0378)
  - Ohana, Maurice, 1913-1992 Llanto por Ignacio Sanchez Mejias, 1966, 1 score (122 pages); Print M. R. Braun/G. Billaudot Instrumentation: For vocal soloist (baritone), narrator, women's choir, and orchestra. Contains a small number of performance markings, including the removal of some measures. Text by Federico Garcia Lorca. Additional name: Garcia Lorca, Federico, 1898-1936 (Box 18, Folder 0379)
  - Ohana, Maurice, 1913-1992 Signes, 1967, 1 score (38 pages); Holograph (facsimile) Amphion Editions Musicales Instrumentation: For flute, 2 zithers (1 player), piano, and percussion (4 players) The only marking is a question about a pitch accidental on page 8. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 18, Folder 0380)
  - Olazábal, Tirso de, 1924-1960 Sonatina para piano, 1958, 1 score (11 pages); Print (photocopy) Ricordi Americana Instrumentation: For solo piano Most of the performance markings are from the original source of the photocopy. The date of 1954 has been added in the caption. (Box 18, Folder 0381)
  - Oliver, Stephen, 1950-1992 Man of feeling: a sketch for soprano, baritone and piano, 1983, 1 score (14 pages); Print (photocopy) Novello Instrumentation: For soprano, baritone, and piano Contains many performance markings including changes to octave registers and cuts. Incomplete. Composer's facsimile. (Box 18, Folder 0382)
  - Oliveros, Pauline, 1932- Gathering together: for piano eight hands, 1983, 1 score (42 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For piano eight hands Contains performance markings. (Box 18, Folder 0383)
  - Olsen, Poul Rovsing, 1922-1982 Duo: for accordion and piano, 1969, 1 score (16 pages); Print Hohner Verlag Trossingen Instrumentation: For accordion and piano Piano part marked for performance. (Box 18, Folder 0384)
  - Olsen, Poul Rovsing, 1922-1982 Nocturnes, opus 21, 1977, 1 score (13 pages); Print Wilhelm Hansen Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains a small number of performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. Also includes an annotated program for a November 7 1983 performance of the Nocturnes at Radiohusets Koncertsal. (Box 18, Folder 0385)
  - Olsen, Poul Rovsing, 1922-1982 Sonate II, opus 57, 1967, 1 score (17 pages); Holograph (Photoreproduction) Instrumentation: For solo piano Extensively marked for performance. (Box 18, Folder 0386)
  - Ornstein, Leo, 1892-2002 Legend nos. I [and] II, undated, 1 score (19 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Legend one is print. (Box 18, Folder 0387)
  - Ornstein, Leo, 1892-2002 Piano sonata no. 7, 1988, 1 score (44 pages); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings, including dynamics and tempo markings. (Box 18, Folder 0388)
  - Pade, Steen Florilegium for Klavier: 8 bagateller, 1979, 1 score (15 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano The last movement contains some performance markings, including a measure of additional music. (Box 18, Folder 0389)
  - Palmer, Robert, 1915-2010 Concerto for piano and string orchestra, 1969, 1 score (50 pages); Holograph (Ozalid reproduction) Instrumentation: For piano and string orchestra Markings include additional dynamics, changes to pitch accidentals, and other changes to the score. Score is marked "R. P. Copy" in caption. (Box 19, Folder 0390)
  - Palmer, Robert, 1915-2010 Sonata for cello and piano, 1978, 1 score (37 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For violoncello and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 19, Folder 0391)
  - Palmer, Robert, 1915-2010 Unidentified piano piece, undated, 1 score (12 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Markings on the photocopy are difficult to distinguish from markings on the original source. Photocopy of holograph, not Piano Sonata #2, Piano Sonata #3, or 3 preludes. Incomplete. The first movement, marked "To John Kirkpatrick", appears to be complete on pages 1-6. The incomplete second movement consists of pages 7-8. There is a gap until pages 17-18. It is unclear if this is the beginning of the third movement. There is a double bar at the end of page 18. Two unnumbered pages contain sketch materials. (Box 19, Folder 0392)
  - Perle, George, 1915-2009 Ballade for piano, 1983, 1 score (24 pages); Print Henmar/C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff, dated Aldeburgh '85. (Box 19, Folder 0393)
  - Philipp, Isidore, 1863-1958 Complete school of technic: for the pianoforte, 1908, 1 score (115 pages); Print Theodore Presser Instrumentation: For solo piano The only markings are circles around a few of the exercise numbers. (Box 19, Folder 0394)
  - Piazzolla, Astor Angel: for piano, 1968, 1 score (7 pages); Print Tonos Instrumentation: For solo piano The only marking is on the title page, beginning "This set is clearly of the jazz-influenced … " (Box 19, Folder 0395)
  - Piazzolla, Astor Estaciones (Jahreszeiten): for piano, 1970, 1 score (11 pages); Print Tonos Instrumentation: For solo piano The only markings are comments on the title page. (Box 19, Folder 0396)
  - Piazzolla, Astor Jeanne Y Paul: tango malinconico: el penultimo: milonga sin parabras, 1973, 1 score (9 pages); Print A.A.A. Prologo/Tonos Instrumentation: For solo voice or instrument and piano The only markings are comments on the title page. (Box 19, Folder 0397)
  - Piazzolla, Astor Libertango, 1975, 1 score (33 pages); Print Edizioni Curci/Paganmusic Instrumentation: For solo piano The only markings are comments on the title page. Signed by Mikhashoff, and dated Aug. 5, 1988, Darmstadt. (Box 19, Folder 0398)
    Libertango -- Meditango -- Undertango -- Violentango -- Amelitango -- Novitango -- Tristango.
  - Piazzolla, Astor Musica de Buenos Aires, 1973, 1 score (17 pages); Print Editorial lagos Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains a very small number of markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 19, Folder 0399)
    Onda nueve -- Oda para un hippie -- Preludio 9 -- Divertimento 9.
  - Piazzolla, Astor Preludio 9, Fuga 9, Divertimento 9, 1973, 1 score (18 pages); Print Editorial Lagos/Tonos Instrumentation: For solo piano The only markings are comments on the title page, including "All excellent for transcription for full ensemble". Signed by Mikhashoff, dated Jan. 15 1993, Buffalo. (Box 19, Folder 0400)
  - Piazzolla, Astor Reunion cumbre, 1975, 1 score (36 pages); Print Editorial Lagos Instrumentation: For piano, bandoneon and baritone saxophone The only markings are Mikhashoff's comments on the verso of the title page. Hace veinte años -- Cierra tus ojos y escucha -- Años de soledad -- Deus Xango -- Veinte años despues -- Reminiscencia -- Reunion cumbre. (Box 19, Folder 0401)
  - Piazzolla, Astor Revolucionario, 1974, 1 score (36 pages); Print Editorial Lagos Instrumentation: Primarily for piano; the 5th-6th works with bandoneon; the 7th work with violin. The only markings are Mikhashoff's comments on the page facing the title page. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 19, Folder 0402)
    Revolucionario: tango -- Coral: coral -- Kicho: tango -- Fuga 9 -- Homenaje a Córdoba: milonga -- Mar del Plata 70: tango -- Imágenes 676: tango.
  - Piazzolla, Astor Tangazo, 1975, 1 score (13 pages); Print Editorial Lagos Instrumentation: Piano conductor score with indications for instrumentation for chamber orchestra The only markings are Mikhashoff's comments on the verso of the title page. (Box 19, Folder 0403)
  - Pickard, Kevin Barry Maculations on an old Irish dumpe: for clarinet and piano, 1975, 1 score (6 pages) and 1 part (2 pages); Holograph Instrumentation: For clarinet and piano Contains pencil additions and changes to the score. Clarinet part is a photocopy. (Box 19, Folder 0404)
  - Pinto, Octavio, 1890-1950 Scenas infantis (Memories of childhood), 1932, 1 score (13 pages); Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Includes texts of accompanying poems, in Portuguese with English translations. (Box 19, Folder 0405)
    Run, run! -- Ring around the rosy! -- March, little soldier! -- Sleeping time -- Hobby-horse.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Slow sinks the sun, 1916, 1 score (5 pages); Print (photocopy) G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains one note about interpretation of the rhythm. (Box 19, Folder 0406)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Aubade. Concerto chorégraphique pour piano et dix-huit instruments., undated, 1 score ( 23 pages); Print Rouart-Lerolle Instrumentation: For piano and 18 instruments Solo piano part marked for performance. (Box 19, Folder 0407)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Concerto en ré mineur pour deux pianos et orchestre, 1933, 2 scores (53 pages each); Print Instrumentation: For 2 pianos; originally for 2 pianos and orchestra Contains only a small number of performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 19, Folder 0408)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Histoire de Babar, le petit éléphant pour récitant et piano, 1969, 1 score (31 pages); Print J. & W. Chester Instrumentation: For reciter and piano Score is marked with letters A-Y that mark the major sections of the piece. Photocopied pages have been attached in some places to facilitate page turning. Text by Jean de Brunhoff. Additional name: Brunhoff, Jean de, 1899-1937 (Box 19, Folder 0409)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Tombeau, 1925, 1 score (4 pages); Print (photocopy) Heugel Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains only one fingering marked on score. Text by Philippe de Ronsard. From the volume titled Chansons et mélodies. Additional name: Ronsard, Pierre de, 1524-1585 (Box 19, Folder 0410)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Trio pour piano, hautbois et basson, 1954, 1 score (34 pages); Print Wilhelm Hansen Instrumentation: For piano, oboe, and bassoon Extensively marked for performance. (Box 19, Folder 0411)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953 Drei Stücke: für Klavier, 1978, 1 score (27 pages); Print C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains only a small number of fingerings. (Box 19, Folder 0412)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953 Tales of the old grandmother: for piano, 1948, 1 score (11 pages); Print MCA Music Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains one marking on page 7. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 19, Folder 0413)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953 Toccate pour piano, op. 11, 1912, 1 score (13 pages); Print Robert Forberg Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings, including fingerings and a possible cut. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 19, Folder 0414)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953 Mimoletnosti [Visions fugitives, op. 22], 1917, 1 score (27 pages); Print IzdatelŒstvo Muzyka Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings throughout. (Box 19, Folder 0415)
  - Putsché, Thomas, 1929- Hexachord fantasies: nineteen pieces for piano, 1967, 1 score (45 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid reproduction) Instrumentation: For solo piano First ten pieces contain performance markings. (Box 20, Folder 0416)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943 Concerto no. 3 in d minor: op. 30: for piano and orchestra, undated, 1 score (79 pages); Print International Music Company Instrumentation: For two pianos; originally for piano and orchestra Contains extensive performance markings. Signed Mikhashoff (Ronald MacKay). Caution: loose pages. (Box 20, Folder 0417)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943 V moei dushe (In my soul): op. 14, no. 10, undated, 2 score (6 pages each); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and piano Both photocopies are extensively marked with transliterated text and performance markings. (Box 20, Folder 0418)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943 Siren' (Les Lilas), op. 21, no. 5, 1947, 1 score (pages 28-30); Print (photocopy) A. Gutheil/Boosey & Hawkes Instrumentation: For voice and piano Marked with transliteration of Russian text. From Romansy, op. 21. (Box 20, Folder 0419)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943 V molchan'I nochi tainoi = Lorsque la nuit m'entoure, op. 4 no. 3, 1947, 1 score (pages 7-11); Print (photocopy) A. Gutheil/Boosey & Hawkes Instrumentation: For voice and piano Marked with transliteration of Russian text. From Romansy, op. 4. (Box 20, Folder 0420)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943 Album for the piano, 1925, 1 score (54 pages); Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. There is a text added above measures in the Elegie, op. 3 no. 1. Missing pages 55-63. (Box 20, Folder 0421)
    Prélude in C-sharp minor, op. 3, no. 2 -- Elégie in E-flat minor, op. 3, no. 1 -- Mélodie in E, op. 3, no. 3 -- Sérénade in B-flat minor, op. 3, no. 5 -- Valse in A, op. 10, no. 2 -- Polichinelle, op. 3, no. 4 -- Prélude in G minor, op. 23, no. 5 -- Barcarolle in G minor, op. 10, no. 3.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Album of Maurice Ravel Masterpieces, 1937, 1 score (70 pages); Print Edward B. Marks Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. The Pavane is marked with indications of instrumentation for an arrangement. Pages 69-70 are replaced with pages 125-126 from another edition. (Box 20, Folder 0422)
    Alborada del gracioso -- La vallee des cloches -- Une barque sur l'ocean -- Noctuelles -- Pavane -- Oiseux tristes -- Lento: excerpt from the string quartet / arranged by Felix Guenther -- Jeux d'eau.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Chansons madécasses, 1926, 1 score (20 pages) and 2 parts; Print Durand Instrumentation: For voice, flute, violoncello, and piano Score and both parts contain performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 20, Folder 0423)
    Nahandove -- Aoua! Aoua! -- Il est doux.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Histoires naturelles, 1907, 1 score (23 pages); Print (photocopy) Durand Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. Text by Jules Renard. Additional name: Renard, Jules, 1864-1910 (Box 20, Folder 0424)
    Le paon -- Le grillon -- Le cygne -- Le martin-pêcheur-- La pindate.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Tzigane, rapsodie de concert pour violon et orchestre, 1948, 1 score (31 pages reproduced on 16 leaves); Print (photocopy) Durand Instrumentation: Originally for violin and piano; arranged for violin and orchestra by the composer Contains markings for a structural analysis of the piece. (Box 20, Folder 0425)
  - Rea, John, 1944- Meninas pour piano, 1991, 1 score (44 pages); Print Musicgraphe Editions Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Mikhashoff's re-notated version of the seventh piece is inserted (1 leaf of ink manuscript). "Variations transformelles sur les "Kinderszenen de Robert Schumann". Typescript program notes (2 leaves) inserted. (Box 20, Folder 0426)
    Von fremden Ländern und Menschen = Gens et pays étrangers = From foreign lands and people; Kuriose Geschichte = Drôle d'histoire = Curious story; Hasche-Mann = Colin-maillard = Blindman's-buff; Bittendes Kind = L'enfant supplie = Pleading child; Glückes genug = Bonheur parfait = Perfect happiness; Wichtige Begebenheit = Un grand événement = Important event; Träumerei = Rêverie = Reverie; Am Kamin = Au coin du feu = By the fireside; Ritter vom Steckenpferd = Chevalier sur le cheval de bois = Knight of the rocking-horse; Fast zu ernst = Presque trop sérieux = Almost too serious; Fürchtenmachen = Croquemitaine = Boogeyman's coming; Kind im Einschlummern = L'enfant s'endort = Child falling asleep; Der Dichter spricht = Le poète parle = The poet speaks.
  - Reich, Willi, 1898-1980 Alban Berg's Wozzeck: a guide to the text and music of the opera, 1952, 1 book (22 pages); Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: Prose work Some text is underlined. (Box 20, Folder 0427)
  - Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936 Sonata in si minore per violino e piano, 1974, 1 score (33 pages) and 1 part (10 pages); Print Ricordi Instrumentation: For violin and piano Contains only a few performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff and dated July 1979, Rome. (Box 20, Folder 0428)
  - Riegger, Wallingford, 1885-1961 Blue voyage: (after Conrad Aiken), 1929, 10 pages; Print (photocopy) G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration of the piece. (Box 20, Folder 0429)
  - Rihm, Wolfgang Fremde Szenen I: Versuche für Klaviertrio, 1982, 1 score (18 pages); Print (reproduction of manuscript) Universal Edition Instrumentation: For violin, violoncello, and piano Extensively marked for performance. (Box 20, Folder 0430)
  - Rihm, Wolfgang Fremde Szenen II: Versuche für Klaviertrio, 1983, 1 score (75 pages); Print (reproduction of manuscript) Universal Edition Instrumentation: For violin, violoncello, and piano Contains (Box 20, Folder 0431)
  - Rihm, Wolfgang Fremde Szenen III: Versuche für Klaviertrio, 1984, 1 score (29 pages); Print (reproduction of manuscript) Universal Edition Instrumentation: For violin, violoncello, and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 20, Folder 0432)
  - Rijnvos, Richard, 1964- Study in 5 parts for piano (1986/87), 1987, 1 score (25 pages); Manuscript (Photoreproduction) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains one instance of fingerings. Typescript (1 leaf) list of corrected mistakes inserted. (Box 20, Folder 0433)
  - Rodriguez, Robert Xavier Tango from Tango, 1985, 3 parts; Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For violin, accordion, and piano Piano part contains performance markings. Excerpt from the opera in one act for tenor and chamber ensemble. Note in caption of piano part: ""This piano part may be played: 1) with the other parts as a trio for violin, accordion, and piano; 2) with the accordion part as an accorion [sic] / piano duo; or, 3) as a piano solo." (Box 20, Folder 0434)
  - Rorem, Ned, 1923- Trio: [for] flute, violoncello and piano, 1966, 1 score (26 pages) and 2 parts; Print C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For flute, violoncello and piano Score and parts contain performance markings. (Box 20, Folder 0435)
  - Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937 Jazz dans la nuit, 1929, 1 score (7 pages); Print Durand Instrumentation: For voice and piano Some measures have been numbered. Text by René Dommange. Additional name: Dommange, René (Box 20, Folder 0436)
  - Ruders, Poul, 1949- Break-Dance, 1984, 1 score (14 pages); Holograph (Photocopy) Distributed by Wilhem Hansen Instrumentation: For 2 trumpets, 3 trombones, and piano Score is marked for performance. Mikhashoff re-notated the piano part for ease of reading. The manuscripts were attached with tape. They are now in a separate envelope. Nine manuscript leaves of Mikhashoff's re-notated version serve as a separate part from page 7-14 of the score. (Box 21, Folder 0437)
  - Ruders, Poul, 1949- Recitatives and arias (1979), 1979, 1 score (76 pages) and 1 part (26 pages); Holograph (Photocopy) Instrumentation: For small orchestra and piano The score contains a small number of performance markings and some passages of the piano solo have been darkened. The piano part (30 p.) is a manuscript of Mikhashoff's re-notated version of the solo. It also contains performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. Written for Yvar Mikhashoff. (Box 21, Folder 0438)
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985 Pentagram no. 4: the human way, 1952, 1 score (16 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid reproduction) Composers Facsimile Edition Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains corrections to the score. (Box 21, Folder 0439)
    1. Pomp -- 2. Yearning -- 3. Irony -- 4. Overcoming -- 5. Peace.
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985 Quintet: for strings and piano, 1952, 2 scores (34 pages each) and 4 parts; Holograph (Ozalid reproduction) American Composers Alliance Instrumentation: For 2 violins, viola, violoncello, and piano The unbound score contains a small number of performance markings. Movement 1 is marked "Corrected"; movements 2-3 are marked "not corrected". (Box 21, Folder 0440)
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985 Pentagram no. 3. Stars, undated, 1 score (2 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains a small number of performance markings. (Box 21, Folder 0441)
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985 Pentagram no. 3. Sun burst, undated, 1 score (2 pages); Manuscript (photocopy) American Composers Alliance Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. (Box 21, Folder 0442)
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985 Syntony: for piano solo, 1968, 1 score (23 pages); Holograph (Ozalid reproduction) American Composers Alliance Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. (Box 21, Folder 0443)
    Dithryamb -- Eclogue -- Oracle -- Apotheosis.
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985 Three melodies: for flute, 1978, 1 score (12 pages) and 2 parts; Print Joshua Corporation Instrumentation: For flute, violoncello, and piano Score and parts marked for performance, including measure numbers. (Box 21, Folder 0444)
  - Rzewski, Frederic Four pieces for piano, 1977, 1 score (36 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Mikhashoff's manuscript (2 leaves) of re-notated versions of pages 25-26 are attached. (Box 21, Folder 0445)
  - Rzewski, Frederic Winnsboro cotton mill blues: for two pianos, 1980, 1 score (26 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For two pianos Contains performance markings. The fourth of his North American ballads. (Box 21, Folder 0446)
  - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 2e concerto pour piano et orchestre, op. 22: arranged for 2 pianos, 1948, 2 scores (65 pages, 83 pages); Print Durand & Schoenewerk, G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For two pianos; originally for piano and orchestra Both the Durand and Schirmer scores contain performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. The Durand copy is in very poor condition. (Box 21, Folder 0447)
  - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 Septet, opus 65, 1956, 1 score (35 pages) and 6 parts; Print International Music Company Instrumentation: For trumpet, 2 violins, viola, violoncello, double bass, and piano The score contains performance markings, including the deletion of measures. (Box 21, Folder 0448)